NETFLIX オリジナルシリーズ
〜
BASED ON THE COMIC SERIES
BLAZING TRANSFER STUDENT
（天の声）
炎の転校生とは
Blazing Transfer Students are agents
問題がある学校に潜入し
悪を断つ
who infiltrate troubled schools
and stamp out the evil that afflicts them.
エージェントたちの
名称である
今 ここに
This is the story
of seven new Blazing Transfer Students.
新たに７人の
炎の転校生が誕生した
〜
（滝沢(たきざわ)）早速だが 転校だ
It's time for your first transfer.
（７人）おお！
（コタキ）目から映像 出てる
-His eyes are projectors!
-That is totally awesome!
（キリヤマ）でら すげえ！
（ビデオのナレーション）
全寮制 華麗成(かれいなる)学園では
Kareinaru Academy is a boarding school
that supports students academically
and provide them with a healthy
生徒たちは勉学に励みながら
健やかで充実した…
-That is the tea ceremony!
-and fulfilling student life.
（シゲオカ）茶道なんや！
（ナーレション）
学生生活を送ります
卒業生は各方面で活躍
Graduates have gone on
to contribute in many fields.
Kareinaru Academy is a school
that is building a bright future.
華麗成学園は
明るい未来を作る学校です
-So, it's a boarding school?
-I know this place.
（カミヤマ）全寮制の学校か
（ナカマ）
ここ 知ってるぞ
なかなかの進学校や
It's a renowned prep school.
It's pretty darn prestigious.
（キリヤマ）
どえりゃあ いい学校だがね？
But something strange has been happening.
（日花里(ひかり)）
でも 何かが起こっているの
（シゲオカ）ん？ 何かって？
Something strange?
（滝沢）
その問題を探り出し 解決するのが
君たちのミッションだ
It's your mission to figure that out
and resolve it.
今回 転校するのは 日花里君と…
The transfer students
for this mission are Hikari and...
（シゲオカ）えっ 日花里ちゃん？
Really? Hikari?
Those who get hit by the ball.
あのボールに当たった人よ！
（７人）えっ？
-Excuse me?
-What?
うわっ！
SPINNING
（ハマダ）
ルールなら しかたない
If that's the rule, I have no choice.
（カミヤマ）おお〜
普通にできんのぉ？
Can't you just choose normally?
TOTAL Z!!
（日花里）ここね
This is Kareinaru Academy.
華麗成学園
日本全国300万人の高校生を
対象とした学力テストで
Three million high school students
take the achievement test in Japan.
上位100人中55人が
ここの学校の生徒やった
It turns out 55 of the top 100
go to this school.
（キリヤマ）
はあ！ さすが進学校だがね
That is one hell of a prep school!
For your information, I was number one.
ちなみに１位は僕やってんけどね
Is that so?
あら そうかい
Are you students here?
ここの生徒か！
Yes. We are transfer students.
はい 転校生です
そう
-You are?
-Yes.
（ハマダ）はい
最近 気味悪いんだよな〜 この学校
Recently...
bizarre stuff has been happening
at this school.
まったく
毎晩 毎晩 何やってんだか…
They're up to something weird
every damn night.
C OR K
KAREINARU ACADEMY
Everyone.
（教師）皆さん
皆さん ちょっと聞いてください
Everyone, please listen to me
for a moment.
本日 転校してきた４名です
These four new students
transferred to our school today.
Kakeru Hamada.
ハマダ駆(かける)君
よろしくお願いします
Nice to meet you.
誰も見てへん
Nobody is even looking.
どうも！ あちき
転校生のキリヤマ駆でござる
Hello! I'm a transfer student!
My name is Kakeru Kiriyama!
Transfer student?
（男子１）転校生？
（男子２）新しい生徒…
New students.
（女子１）
だったら 仲間にしなくちゃ
Then, we must make them our friends.
We must make them one of us.
（女子２）私たちの仲間に…
SPRINKLING
（米田(よねだ)）ハア…
（チャイム）
SPICE LEVEL 2
（男子１）さあ 学食の時間だよ
It's time for lunch in the cafeteria.
（男子２）
ようこそ 華麗成学園へ！
Welcome to Kareinaru Academy!
（女子１）
まずは 学食！
案内しますよ さあ
First, we will show you the way
to the cafeteria.
（女子２）
うちの学食
最高においしいんだよ！
Our cafeteria lunches are
incredibly delicious!
（日花里）へえ〜 おなか すいた！
Really? I'm hungry.
（キリヤマ）
なにぃ ええヤツらだが
These guys are pretty cool!
Come on, guys! Hurry up!
おみゃあらも はよ行こみゃあ
アハハッ
CAFETERIA
Cafeteria Lady! My scores have improved!
（男子３）
おばちゃん！ 成績 上がりました
-Mine have, too.
-That's great.
（男子４）俺も上がりましたよ
（米田）よかったね
（キリヤマ）
おお！ これはカレーの匂いだがや
-I smell curry!
-Cut it out!
（ナカマ）やめろ お前…
No cutting in line! Obey the rules.
おい おい おい！ 横入りするな
ルールを守れ
（キリヤマ）
うざこいな おみゃあは まったく…
What a pain in the neck you are!
（ナカマ）抜かすな言うてん
No cutting in line!
-You caught me.
-Of course I did.
（キリヤマ）バレました？
（ナカマ）当たり前やろ
-Get back there.
-I'm sorry.
（ナカマ）ほら
（キリヤマ）失敬
SWISH
何してんの？
What are you doing?
トッピングじゃ
Making some toppings.
（ナカマ）は？
（日花里）ん？
（ナカマ）うおっ
（キリヤマ）
栄養が違うのじゃ　どうぞ
This makes it more nutritious. Have some.
（日花里）バナナ 嫌い
I hate bananas.
（キリヤマ）無念…
Such a pity!
（ナカマ）
あれ？ カレー 苦手なんか？
What? You don't like curry?
カレーは脂肪と炭水化物の塊だ
Curry is nothing but fat
and carbohydrates.
減量中のボクサーにとっては天敵だ
It's the enemy of a boxer
who is trying to lose weight.
ハマダ君 減量中なの？
Are you trying to lose weight?
No.
（ハマダ）いや…
Do you have a sensitive stomach?
まさか お子様舌か？
うっ！
Really?
（キリヤマ）え？ アッハッハ！
ただ辛いもんが嫌いなもんで
そうやって…
Why didn't you just say
you don't like spicy...
BLOW
うっ！
ん？
There was rice on your cheek.
（ハマダ）ご飯粒が…
（キリヤマ）ああ… すまなんだ
Thanks.
（ナカマ）
にしても
みんな 随分と勉強熱心やな
You know, it's amazing
how hard everyone studies.
That's right.
They are such admirable students.
（校長）そうなんだよ〜
感心な生徒たちでね
As their principal,
they make me very proud.
校長の私も実に鼻が高い
Principal?
（ハマダ）校長…
So, you're the transfer students.
（校長）君たち 転校生だね
What do you think
of our cafeteria's curry?
どうだい？ 学食のカレーは
It was awesome. I finished it so quickly.
最高です
ペロッと食べちゃいました
You're a fast eater!
食べんの 早っ！
I see!
そうかい
Then I will serve you another bowl.
じゃあ お代わりをあげよう
SQUIRT
What's with that device?
（ナカマ）
どんなシステムや？ これ
Thank you.
（日花里）ありがとうございます
（校長）うん 気持ちいいね〜
I'm glad that you like it.
Please, eat all you like.
どんどん食べなさい
（ナカマ）あの 校長
Excuse me, Principal.
ぶしつけな質問で 大変恐縮ですが
I apologize for the rude question,
この学校で何かトラブルって
あったりしますか？
but does this school have any problem?
（校長）え？ トラブル？
What? Problem?
いいや
No.
But a man from the neighborhood
complained to us.
ほんだけど
近所の殿方が 苦情言っとったで
なんか 夜がどうとか…
He said there were incidents at night.
夜？ 夜？
Night? What about it?
ん？ 何のことだろう
I wonder what it could be.
でも 教えてくれて ありがとう
Anyway, thank you for letting me know.
I will look into it.
私も確認しておこう
おっ！ 君も お代わりだ
Oh! Here are seconds for you, too.
（男子）ありがとうございます
-Thank you.
-Enjoy!
（ハマダ）ごちそうさまでした
Thank you for the meal.
あなた カレーが嫌いなのね？
You don't like curry, do you?
だったら
この学校から出ていきなさい
Then leave this school! Leave now!
今すぐにでも
"At last"?
（ハマダ）“ついに”？
AT LAST, OUR ONLY DISH IS CURRY
I thought students at prep schools
（日花里）進学校とはいえ
もっと
伸び伸びした校風だったはずだけど
had a lot more freedom
to do what they want.
Anyway, there haven't been
any problems yet.
ほんでも まあ
今んとこ 特に問題にゃあが
みんな 真面目やし
校長は気のええ おっちゃんやし
They are all diligent students,
and the principal is a nice guy.
学食のカレーは
どえりゃあ うみゃあしな
The cafeteria's curry
is super delicious, too!
ハハハッ…
It's a big problem
because they only serve curry!
（ハマダ）
学食がカレーだけって大問題だろ
（キリヤマ）ハハハッ
（ナカマ）まあまあ まあまあ
Now, wait a second.
At any rate, nothing has happened today.
とりあえず 今日は何もなしか
（ハマダ）うん
RATTLING
What's going on?
（ナカマ）これは…
RATTLING
（ハマダ）おい どうしたんだ？
What's wrong?
RATTLING
（日花里）うう… うう…
日花里殿？
Hikari?
おい
Hey!
（日花里）うう… うう…
うっ！
（ナカマ･キリヤマ）うわ〜！
シャー！
（ナカマ･キリヤマ）ぎゃ〜！
（ハマダ）おい！
Hey!
Don't run in the halls!
廊下を走るな！
（ナカマ）
そんなん言ってる場合ちゃうやろ！
This is no time for that!
-Hurry! Hurry!
-Let's hide!
（キリヤマ）はよ はよ！
（ナカマ）隠れよう！
Here! It's open!
開(あ)いてる！
ハア ハア…
What the heck is going on?
Even Hikari went nuts!
どうなってんのや？ あれ
日花里ちゃんまで！
（キリヤマ）
何か分からせんけど
急に“おぎゃ〜”ってなって
I can't understand it!
She suddenly started snarling!
顔に“２”と書いてあった
-Number two was written on her forehead!
-Something is wrong!
（ハマダ）
突然 何が起こったんだ？
（キリヤマ）ぎゃ〜！
（ナカマ）なに？
-What's wrong?
-What the heck is this?
何だて これ？
（キリヤマ）おみゃあもだが！
（ナカマ）えっ？
You have it, too!
あっ！ さっきまで なかったのに…
It wasn't there earlier!
（生徒）シャア…
（キリヤマ･ナカマ）うわ〜！
（ナカマ）うわ〜！
Look! There are so many of them!
おい！ いっぱい いる！
ぎゃ〜！
（ハマダ）くそ〜！
Damn it!
はっ？
My punches are not working!
俺のパンチが効かない
They're bouncing back like zombies!
ゾンビのように
何度も よみがえってくるぞ
ってか こいつらゾンビや！
That's because they are zombies!
（ハマダ）ええっ！
（ナカマ）
あれ 数字の２じゃなくて
That's not the number two!
ゾンビの“Ｚ”！
That's the letter Z for zombie!
Z for zombie?
ゾンビのＺ？
ぎゃ〜！
（ハマダ）キリヤマ！
Kiriyama!
Don't, Hamada! It's too late!
（ナカマ）よせよ！ 間に合わなへん
いや！ いや！
いや〜っ
-Wait!
-I swear I'll help you later!
（ハマダ）あとで必ず助ける
（キリヤマ）待って…
-Wait! Wait!
-Let's go!
（ハマダ）行くぞ！
（ナカマ）ごめん！
-Sorry!
-Wait!
待って〜！
（ピアノの不協和音）
（ハマダ）
何だ？ あの気持ち悪い踊りは
What is with that creepy dance?
ゾンビダンスか？
Is that the zombie dance?
日花里ちゃんまで…
Even Hikari is doing it?
“華麗なる”どころか
ゾンビ学園やな
This school isn't making a bright future.
It's making zombies!
何か手はないのか？
Is there anything we can do?
そうや
I just remembered!
アメリカに
ゾンビと戦ってる友人がおる
I have an American friend
who fights zombies. I'll ask him.
そいつに聞いてみよう
An American? Fighting zombies?
アメリカ人？ ゾンビ？
ああ あの国はゾンビだらけや
Yes, that country is full of zombies.
待ってろ
Hold on.
アメリカ人？ ゾンビ？
An American? Fighting zombies?
（ナカマ）ハイ ニック
（ニック）
ハイ ナカマ
（英語で）
学校の生徒たちがゾンビになった
どうしたらいい？
（ニックのため息）
（英語で）
日本のような小さな島国で
ゾンビが出たら
もう おしまいだろ
（英語で）クソッたれ
いいから対策だけ教えてくれ
（英語で）
奴らを倒すには
脳みそをぶち抜くか首を落とすかだな
（ナカマ:英語で）
後ろを見ろ！
（英語で）
そう 生き残るには
後方に注意を払うことも重要
ギァアアア
（英語で）サヨナラ ニック…
（ナカマのため息）
（ハマダ）キリヤマ！
It's Kiriyama!
（ハマダ）
あいつ 何をのんきに
カレーなんか食ってんだ？
What's with him?
Why is he happily eating curry?
That is not what he is doing! Watch!
違う！ よく見ろ
Even Kiriyama has turned into a zombie?
キリヤマまでゾンビに…
That's it!
そうか
これが完全なＺになったとき
僕もゾンビになってまうんや
When this becomes a complete letter,
I'll become a zombie, too.
お前まで！ なぜだ？
Not you, too!
考えられる原因は１つしかない
I can think of only one cause.
（ハマダ）学食のカレーだと？
The cafeteria's curry?
（ナカマ）
ああ！
考えられる原因は それしかない
Right! That's the only cause
I can think of.
僕の計算によると…
Based on my calculation...
あのカレーを
特盛りで約3.5杯食べると
you become a zombie after eating
about 3.5 large servings of the curry.
完全なゾンビになる
How did you calculate that?
どう計算したんだ
いや それより…
Forget about that.
生徒をゾンビにして
何のメリットがある？
What's the point of turning them
into zombies?
それは 学食のおばちゃんに
聞くしかないやろ
Only the cafeteria lady can answer that.
No way! No way!
ちょっと ちょっと
ちょっと ちょっと！
Get them!
倒して！
いけ！
うわ〜！
（ハマダ）ナカマ！
Nakama!
（ナカマ）
大丈夫 ここは僕が食い止める
先に行け！
I'll hold them back. You go on ahead!
（ハマダ）大丈夫か？
-Are you sure?
-Don't underestimate my brainpower!
（ナカマ）
僕の頭脳なめんなよ　早く行け！
Hurry!
（ハマダ）ここは任せたぞ
-I'll leave them to you.
-Hurry!
（ナカマ）行け 行け！
あ〜！ やっぱ無理〜！
I can't handle them!
（ハマダ）
“おいしいカレーで
学力と体力をパワーアップ”
"Improve brainpower and strength
with delicious curry.
“カレーパウダーＺ”？
Curry Powder Z."
In the blink of an eye,
Hamada exhibited his supernatural vision.
（天の声）
ハマダが瞬きした瞬間
超人的な視力が発揮されたわけよ
（ハマダ）“副作用 ゾンビ化”
"Side effects, turning into a zombie.
“生産者… なべうし”？
Manufacturer,
Nabeushi"?
However, he can't read
difficult Chinese characters.
（天の声）
ただし 難しい漢字は読めない
That curry is turning them into zombies!
（ハマダ）
それがゾンビカレーのもとか！
あなたは…
You!
I'm so sorry!
ごめんなさい！
I didn't know this would happen!
こんなことになるなんて
思わなかったのよ
だって小さい文字だったから
ゾンビの部分に気付かなかったし
It was written so small,
I didn't notice the zombie part.
みんな 夜な夜な
ゾンビに姿を変えるし
They all turn into zombies at night!
おまけに このカレーしか
受け付けない体になっちゃうし
What is worse, this is the only thing
they would eat!
作り続けるしかなかったのよ
I had no choice but to continue making it!
They're just so hungry at this age.
だって食べ盛りだもん
Thank you for explaining everything
before I asked you.
何も言ってないのに
全ての説明 ありがとうございます
校長に渡されたのよ
生徒の学力を上げるためだって
The principal gave it to me.
He said it would improve
the students' performance.
The principal?
校長に？
（米田）急ぎましょう　ねっ
Let's hurry!
（ハマダ）はい
-Okay!
-Hurry.
（米田）急いで 急いで
Hurry.
（ハマダ）米田さん 急いで
-Come on, let's hurry.
-Okay.
（米田）はい はい
（ハマダ）ああ ナカマ
Nakama, you're all right.
無事だったか
（米田）ああ…
（ハマダ）
くっそ〜 間に合わなかったか！
Darn it! I'm too late!
（校長）おやおや
You there!
急いで どちらへ お出かけだい？
Where are you rushing off to?
カレーは もういいのか？
Don't you want any more curry?
（校長）困るねえ
You've caused me a lot of trouble
隠し味をバラしてしまっては
by revealing the secret ingredient!
I couldn't keep it a secret any longer,
Principal.
（米田）校長 もう隠しきれないわ
いずれ世間に
この事態がバレるわよ
Eventually, the world would find out.
Find out what?
（校長）この事態？
Nothing is happening here!
何のことだ？
うちの生徒たちは 実に真面目に
勉学に励んでるじゃないか！
We are just supporting
our diligent students
so that they can study harder.
But they turn into zombies every night!
だが 夜は このありさまだ
夜 ゾンビになることが何だ
So, what if they become zombies at night?
成績は上がってるんだ
Their scores are improving!
それで いい大学に行ければ
万々歳じゃないか
Nothing matters as long as
they get into great universities.
我が校の名声だって上がる！
It improves the reputation of this school!
So, that's your plan.
それが目的か
What's wrong with zombies?
（校長）ゾンビの何が悪い？
まあ 多少 見た目は悪いが
They may not look that great,
but in this world, only results matter!
この世は結果が全て！
I am doing the right thing!
私は いいことをやったんだ！
I'll admit. Zombies don't look that bad.
百歩譲って
見た目がゾンビでもいい！
Do you really think so?
えっ いいの？
だが しかし お前がやったことは
大変なルール違反！
However, what you have done
is against the rules!
If this were the Olympics,
it would be considered doping!
オリンピックでやったら
金メダルさえも剥奪される
ドーピングだ！
You would even lose a gold medal!
-Doping?
-That's right!
ドーピングだと？
（ハマダ）そうだ
この世は結果が全てじゃない
Results aren't all that matter
in this world!
お前は 生徒たちの心まで
ゾンビにしたんだよ
You have even turned
these students' minds...
into zombies!
偉そうに… ハッ！
Quit acting so high and mighty!
I'll turn you into a zombie
and shut you up!
ゾンビにして黙らせてやる！
校長 やめて！
Don't, Principal!
俺が本気を出せば
When I get serious,
ここにいる連中ぐらい
全員 ぶっ倒せる
I can beat the crap out of everyone here!
（校長）フフッ 何をぬかす
What a load of shit! Get him!
やれい！
BAM
（校長）えっ… マジで？
What? Seriously?
I will defeat you...
俺は正々堂々と
お前に勝ってやる！
fair and square!
（校長）
うわっ マジで？
ヤ… ヤバいじゃん
Seriously? This is bad!
Curry Powder Z!
カレーパウダーＺ！
校長 何を…
What are you doing, Principal?
今すぐに ムキムキになるぞ
"Put on muscles instantly!
“マッチョらっきょう”！
Macho Rakkyo"!
こうなったら しかたがないだろ
I have no other choice!
What? Macho Rakkyo on Zombie Curry?
ゾンビカレーに
マッチョらっきょうだと！
（校長）うわ〜！
何だ？
What the heck?
What?
えっ！
It's Doping Monster!
ドーピングの化け物め！
うが〜！
う〜！
うわっ！
うが〜！
ううっ…
逃げて！
Run! They're all under the principal's
control!
生徒たちは みんな
校長の指示に従ってるの
They have been ordered to turn others
into zombies!
みんな ゾンビにしろって
命令されてるの
（ハマダ）うわっ！
やめろ！
No!
You should never eat it!
絶対 食べちゃダメ！
I know!
分かってる！
（校長）うが〜！
うっ…
Out of the way!
（校長）どけ どけ どけ〜！
（ハマダ）うわっ！
うわ〜！
あ〜！
うっ！
It's too spicy!
辛〜い 辛い 辛い 辛い
Damn it!
ちくしょう！
"Katatsumuri."
（ハマダ）
〝かたつむり…〞
（ピンポン ピンポン！）
頭が良くなってる！
I'm getting smarter!
（校長）うが〜！
（ハマダ）ううっ…
Have some Macho Rakkyo, too! Here!
（米田）
あなたも
マッチョらっきょう 食べなさい
MACHO RAKKYO
ほら！
ハッ…
I can't! That's considered doping!
ううん ダメだ！
それはドーピングだ
I always obey the rules!
俺はルールを守る！
What?
ええっ…
うが〜！
ハッハッハ
どとめだ！
Now, for the finishing blow!
（天の声）
炎の転校生 ハマダ駆 万事休す
It looks like it's curtains
for Blazing Transfer Student Hamada!
もはや これまでか
Is it the end for him?
だが そのとき ハマダの目は
But then, his eyes locked onto
a certain object.
あるものを見逃さなかった
うおお…
ハマダパワー全開！
Hamada's power at full throttle!
Golden Ball Twister!
ゴールデンボールツイスター！
CRUMBLING
（校長）
そこは反則じゃないのか〜！
Isn't that against the rules?
痛〜い…
That hurts!
（米田）効いた！
It worked!
ゾンビである前に男だったのね
You couldn't bear it
even after you turned into a zombie.
このゾンビは治るのか？
Can these zombies be cured?
何だ？
What is this?
お… おい！ 何だ？
Hey! What's going on?
はっ？ 何だ？
What's happening?
あら？ 何しとったんだで？
What? What happened?
ああ… みんなが元の姿に
Everyone is back to normal.
（スピーカー:滝沢）
ハハハハ！
解毒剤が ばっちり効いたようだな
It seems the antidote has worked.
（日花里）えっ？
What?
この声は…
Isn't that...
-Principal Takizawa?
（３人）滝沢校長！
Thanks to you,
the principal's plot was foiled.
（滝沢）
君たちの活躍により
あの校長の陰謀は くじかれた
華麗成学園は
元の健全な学校に戻るだろう
Kareinaru Academy will return
to being a wholesome school.
でも 校長
But, Principal,
解毒剤があるんやったら
if you had the antidote, why didn't you
give it to us from the start?
初めから持たせてくれたら
よかったじゃないですか
That's right!
そうですよ
I looked absolutely awful
during this mission!
今回 私 かなり
ギリギリな顔をしてた気がします
Now, now.
（滝沢）まあまあ
Please, accept this as my apology.
そこは ひとつ これで…
えっ なにぃ？
What? A reward?
褒美？ ハハハッ
“学食カレー食べ放題券”？
"Cafeteria all-you-can-eat curry ticket"?
I don't want it!
いりません！
So, who did the best during the mission?
（滝沢）
それで 今回は誰が一番だった？
それが…
Well, I was a zombie, so I don't know.
ゾンビになっていたので
分かりませんでした
（滝沢）そうか
I see.
まだまだ調べる必要があるな
Then, we'll have to test them further.
Subtitle translation by Brian Athey